Nikoloz Shvelidze

Full-Stack Software Engineer located in Tbilisi, Georgia Looking for jobs in EU

Contact information

shveloo@gmail.com

See my profiles on GitHub, LinkedIn and Stack Overflow

I'm a full-stack developer specializing in modern, best practices **JavaScript** and related technologies (**Node.js**, **TypeScript**, **React**, **Vue**, **CSS3**, **HTML5**).

I'm always thinking about User Experience and Accessibility.

I always strive for great code quality and readability. Making sure to document everything and write unit tests.

Alongside my jobs, I've worked on various interesting freelance projects.

Apps and Websites I've worked on independently

Food4.ge - a popular recipe and food blogging website in Georgia, launched in 2019.

Created for a client. Coded from scratch, entirely by myself. Includes ecommerce features.

Powered by Node.js (Express) and Vue + Nuxt for hybrid Server Side Rendering, which improves search engine optimization and load times.

Tbilisi Bus - an Android app (ceased operating in 2019).

Public transport app for Tbilisi, Georgia, with over 10 000 users.

First created as part of a hackathon, redesigned several times, grew in popularity over time to reach widespread use throughout the city.

Source code: GitHub.com/shvelo/tbilisi-bus

Employment experience

Backend Developer at Mimi Hearing Technologies

Mar 2022 - present, Full Time, Remote

Working on the Mimi platform backend to ensure smooth operation and enhance hearing experience.

Used technologies: Node.js, Nest.js, MongoDB, TypeORM, Docker, CircleCl.

Senior Software Engineer - Full-Stack at Algea Care

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022, Full Time, Remote

Working with an international team to deliver the best patient experience.

Used technologies: Next.js, Nest.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Redis, TypeORM, React, Grommet,

Tailwind CSS, Docker, AWS, GitHub Actions.

Senior Software Engineer - Full-Stack, Node.js Backend at TulaCo

Jul 2019 - Dec 2021, Full Time, Remote-Hybrid

Working for multiple clients at TulaCo:

Back-End Developer for gopractis.com

Back-End Developer for tryframe.com

Front-End Developer for convoz.com

Back-End Developer for studykik.com

Used technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Twilio, React, Nest.js, Redis, MongoDB, Postgres, TypeORM, AWS.

Software Engineer - Full-Stack, Mobile at Qarva

Apr 2018 - Jul 2019, Full Time

Implementing the new generation of live streaming technologies for IPTV. *Used technologies: HLS (hls.js), MPEG-DASH (Shaka player), FFMPEG, Media Source Extensions, Smart TV APIs.*

Software Engineer - Java EE, Full-Stack at AzRy

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018, Full Time

Creating and maintaining Java EE-based solutions for public transportation and payments.

Used technologies: Java EE, GWT, Sencha GXT, PHP.

Lead Developer - Full-stack, Mobile at Sadili.ge

Jul 2015 - Nov 2017, Full Time

Sadili.ge was an innovative on-demand food delivery service that ceased operating in 2017.

I was responsible for coding a large portion of this service, including the payment and delivery flow. Website powered by Sails.js and Angular.js. Featuring live updates and delivery tracking using websocket technology.

I've also created the Android app used by delivery drivers for this service. *Used technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, Sails.js, Socket.IO, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Java (Android), Kotlin.*

Web / Android Developer at LemonDo Business

Mar 2013 - Jun 2014, Freelance Contractor

Creating and maintaining various apps for in-house and B2B use.

Used technologies: jQuery, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java (Android).

Junior Web Developer at Omedia

Sep 2013 - Nov 2013, Half Time

Creating custom solutions with Drupal.

Used technologies: PHP, Drupal, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

My Skills:

■ Back-end web technologies:

Node.js, TypeScript, Next.js, Ruby on Rails, Java EE, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, Sequelize, Express, Socket.io, ElasticSearch

■ Front-end web technologies:

React, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Angular.js, jQuery, Sails.js, Nest.js SASS, CSS, LESS Gulp, Babel, Webpack, Parcel

Android development:

Java, Kotlin, OKHttp, Retrofit, Conductor, AppCompat, Google Play Services

■ Multimedia:

HTTP Live Streaming, FFMPEG, ISO BMFF, MP4, DASH, Media Source Extensions (MSE) Encrypted Media Extensions (EME)

Ecommerce:

Payments and billing, Delivery management and tracking, Inventory management. Integration with payment processors such as **Stripe**, TBC Ecommerce (ECOMM2), BoG iPay

■ Maps/GIS:

Google Maps (Web, Android), OpenStreetMap, NgMap (Google Maps, OSM), Leaflet, MapBox (Android),

Rendering OpenStreetMap tiles, Self-hosted navigation using GraphHopper, Working with geospatial data in MongoDB.

Source control:

Git, GitLab, GitHub, BitBucket, Cl

Linux systems:

Docker, Docker-Compose, Git-based deployment, SSH, Nginx, OpenWRT, Systemd, Arch Linux.

I've set up a working mail server with Postfix, Dovecot, OpenDKIM and OpenDMARC.

Cloud services:

I have experience working with **Amazon Web Services** (EC2, EBS, ECS, S3, Lambda, CloudWatch, RDS).

For personal projects, I use **Linode**.

■ Game Development:

Godot Engine, LibGDX, HaxeFlixel, Phaser, MelonJS, Tiled

Learning in progress:

I'm actively learning the **Rust** programming language and **React Native**

Education

Studying **Computer Science** at **Georgian Technical University** 2016 - present

My Interests

Photography

I collect vintage film and digital cameras, photography is my #1 hobby.

You can see my work on Unsplash and Flickr.

Most of my photos are available under a Creative Commons license.

Game Development

I develop games as a hobby. I think it provides a good challenge for my programming and logic skills.

My current engine of choice is Godot.

Electronics

I experiment with the Arduino ecosystem and Internet of Things.

Vintage computers

I collect various vintage computers, such as IBM ThinkPads.

Source on GitHub